



Muhammad Asim

Nationality: Pakistani Date of birth: 13 Dec 1994 Gender: Male

Phone number: (+92) 3452556967 Email address: muhammad_asim20@yahoo.com

in LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/muhammad-asim-36865375

• Home: House # 30, Al Moeez Homes 3 Near Shami Road, 25000 Peshawar (Pakistan)

ABOUT ME

Goal-oriented Mechatronics Engineer, having hands-on industrial experience chiefly in the textile sector (non-woven production). Responsible for the design of various mechatronic systems, making use of transducers and actuators. Have a sound knowledge of hydraulic and pneumatic systems, electromechanical systems, and embedded systems. Responsible for the design and analysis different types of automated systems and ensuring their smooth operation. Possess excellent management, and communication, and ama good team player.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sr. Operations Manager

Procon Engineering Pvt Ltd (Masters Group) [Mar 2022 - Aug 2022]

City: Lahore

Country: Pakistan

- Managing Smooth Operations of S 1.6m,2.5m, SS1.6m, SSMMS3.2m, and installation, and commissioning of SSS 2.4m production line under the supervision of Chinese engineers.
- · Promoted positive customer experience through day-to-day supervision and management of Production facility.
- Developed and rolled out new policies designed to bolster productivity and reduce overall production costs.
- Reported issues to higher management with great detail.
- Coordinated leadership workshops to educate team members on best practices to optimize productivity.
- Boosted team member productivity by enhancing performance monitoring and instituting motivational approaches.
- Directed management meetings to enhance collaboration and maintain a culture based on trust and group problemsolving.
- Optimized costs to contribute to productivity, cost development, and proficiency of central fulfilment operations.
- \bullet Developing & Implementation of SOPs, Production & Process flow charts.
- · Planning, installation, and managing of new plant installations.
- · Ensuring Quality as per requirements.
- Implementation of 5S' with a liaison of OPEX & Lean.
- Complaint Handling & Liaison with Sales Team.
- · Raw Materials Planning.
- Periodic Maintenance of Plants.

Sr. Manager Production

FB Textile Pvt Ltd [Jul 2020 – Jan 2022]

City: Haripur **Country:** Pakistan

- · Managing installation, commissioning, operations, and smooth production of SSS 3.2m production line.
- Determined suitable crew requirements, scheduled employees, and worked with human resources to meet changing production schedules.
- Assessed manufacturing processes and recommended improvements to increase productivity.
- · Monitored and supported the progress of plant production orders by managing store capacity.
- Managed and implemented marketing activities through research and strategic planning,
- Investigated and implemented ideas for quality improvement, increased productivity, and cost reduction.
- Worked with quality manager to achieve proper segregation and recycling of waste.
- Partnered with leadership on recruiting, hiring, and coaching production personnel.
- Resolved issues quickly to maintain productivity goals.
- Applied lean practices to balance workflow and eliminate unnecessary steps.
- Delivered direct feedback to Directors regarding project visibility and status.
- Estimated labour requirements to support anticipated workload.

- Managed internal operational standards and productivity targets.
- Managed continuous improvement initiatives to drive gains in quality, flow, and output.
- Addressed personnel issues and scheduling conflicts promptly.

Sr. Manager Installations, Production & Operations

QR Textile Pvt Ltd [Oct 2020 – Jan 2022]

City: Haripur **Country:** Pakistan

· Managing installation, commissioning, operation, and smooth production of SXMS 2.4m production line.

Operations, Production & Maintenance Engineer

Zamoung Textile, Deans Industries Pvt Ltd [May 2015 - Jun 2020]

City: Peshawar **Country:** Pakistan

- Managing installation, commissioning, operation, and smooth production of SS 2.4m and SMXS2.4m production lines.
- Supported machine operators in the setup and operation of production equipment resulting in efficient runs.
- Reduced process bottlenecks by training and coaching employees on practices, procedures and performance strategies.
- Organized work to meet demanding production goals.
- · Increased profit by streamlining operations.
- Established positive and effective communication among unit staff and organization leadership, reducing miscommunications and missed deadlines.
- Volunteered for additional assignments during peak work periods to keep tasks on schedule.
- Examined incoming materials and compared them to documentation for accuracy and quality.
- · Assembled products according to changing daily work orders and specific customer needs.
- Used hand trucks and forklifts to load, unload, and transport items.
- Supported production needs by performing routine tasks using standard procedures and equipment.
- Maintained maximum organization and productivity by properly sorting project components on worktables.
- Adjusted machines to increase productivity for runs.
- · Identified procedure or process changes required to improve performance and productivity.
- Used equipment properly to avoid workplace hazards or injuries.
- Documented production information via daily system logs and discussed it with the director.
- Worked in a matrix management environment with oversight of division-level managers, operations, sales, finance, human resources, safety, and compliance.
- Implemented process improvement to shape organizational culture, optimize procedures for higher efficiency and help the company evolve and grow.

FINAL YEAR PROJECT

Petri nets modelling for the manufacturing automation system using virtual engineering

Tools: PLC (S7-1200), TIA by Siemens, MATLAB, PETRI NETS

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

BSC Mechatronics Engineering

University Of Engineering & Technology Peshawar [2011 – 2015]

Website: https://www.uetpeshawar.edu.pk

EXTRA-CURRICULAR & CO-CURRICULAR

Seminars/Workshops Organized & Attended

- Workshop on "AUTONOMOUS ROBOT MAKING", NUST, 2011.
- · Workshop on "Introduction to PLC", 2012, Organized by HoD Telecomat College of Engineering
- Seminar on introduction to engineering education research (EER) IN PAKISTAN NAVY
- ENGINEERING COLLEGE (PNEC),2012
- The 27th IEEEP All Pakistan StudentSeminar,2012
- Workshop on "Line Following Robots", 2013, Organized by KIET Robotics Club.
- Workshop on "PIC Micro-Controller, 2013, Organized by KIET Robotics.
- Workshop on "Robo Sprint 2013", Conducted by CASE Islamabad, Organized by College of Engineering, PAF-KIET.
- National Conference on Computing & Engineering Technology, organized by Pakistan State Oil,2013
- National Science and Youth Symposium, Organized by GIKI Swabi.

HONOURS AND AWARDS

Academic Awards

- 1st positionin water RocketCompetition in WorldSpace week
- 1st position in annual robotics competition reborn
- 2nd positionin all Pakistan Robotics Competition
- 1st positionin Compentencia Del Robotika
- 1st position in an annual robotics competition

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Pashto

Other language(s):

Urdu

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1

German

LISTENING A1 READING A1 WRITING A1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION A1 SPOKEN INTERACTION A1

English

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING B2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION B2